<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Blog Name</title>
  <subtitle>Blog subtitle</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.url.com/</id>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/"/>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2016-03-23T02:00:00+02:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Reactjs Shopping Lists</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2016/03/23/reactjs-shopping-lists.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2016/03/23/reactjs-shopping-lists.html</id>
    <published>2016-03-23T02:00:00+02:00</published>
    <updated>2016-03-24T20:06:32+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have been recently trying out 
&lt;a href="https://facebook.github.io/react/"&gt;reactjs&lt;/a&gt; and decided to rebuild the shopping list section using it.
 &lt;a href="http://www.my-grocery-price-book.co.za/shopping_lists"&gt;give it a try&lt;/a&gt;, you can login as a Guest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get started with react and rails I used a gem called &lt;a href="https://github.com/reactjs/react-rails"&gt;react-rails&lt;/a&gt;. 
The gem allows you to do server side rendering as well which I thought could be pretty useful. 
Getting everything setup was as simple as following their README and I was building react examples in no time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also added &lt;a href="http://eslint.org/"&gt;eslint&lt;/a&gt; as a linting utility for my .jsx files. Getting this running required nodejs 
and npm. I managed to figure (with a bit of GoOgle) I could install what I needed globally using npm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;npm install -g eslint eslint-config-standard eslint-plugin-standard eslint-plugin-react
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;once installed you create a &lt;a href="https://github.com/my-grocery-price-book/www/blob/1bc730bdb6e9cac48c254f10576f5b96e50336df/.eslintrc"&gt;.eslintrc&lt;/a&gt;
 file and run it as follows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;eslint app/assets/javascripts/**/*
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all I am quite happy with the outcome of the shopping list and also really enjoying using reactjs. 
Next up is figuring out how to write jasmine tests for my react components.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Police your code with Rubocop</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2015/11/03/police-your-code-with-rubocop.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2015/11/03/police-your-code-with-rubocop.html</id>
    <published>2015-11-03T02:00:00+02:00</published>
    <updated>2016-01-29T17:57:50+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Keeping your code on a project in shape is a daily challenge but there is a a ruby gem called 
&lt;a href="https://github.com/bbatsov/rubocop"&gt;rubocop&lt;/a&gt; that can help you with this.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been using &lt;a href="https://github.com/bbatsov/rubocop"&gt;rubocop&lt;/a&gt; on the grocery app and a few other projects for a while 
now. It's is really a great tool to help keep your code quality in check. Rubocop is a Ruby static code analyzer that 
is based on the &lt;a href="https://github.com/bbatsov/ruby-style-guide"&gt;Ruby Style Guide&lt;/a&gt; and 
&lt;a href="https://github.com/bbatsov/rails-style-guide"&gt;Rails Style Guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting started with it is real simple:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-shell"&gt;  gem install rubocop
  rubocop -R # run inside your Rails Project
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might feel that some of these suggestions are splitting hairs. For example things such as single quotes vs double quotes, 
indentations and blank lines. These simple ones are usually easily fixed by using rubocop's builtin autofix functionality. 
Just run &lt;code&gt;rubocop -aR&lt;/code&gt; which will automatically update your code for these more simpler rules.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rules that you feel is against your personal style, eg documenting classes, methods should not start with "get" or 
"set" as it can easily be turned off or tuned by adding a .rubocop.yml to your project root folder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you follow those guideslines and refactor accordly you should end with simpler, more readable and more maintainable
code.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Vagrant and Ansible the ultimate combo</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2015/09/27/vagrant-and-ansible.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2015/09/27/vagrant-and-ansible.html</id>
    <published>2015-09-27T02:00:00+02:00</published>
    <updated>2016-01-29T17:57:50+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So for the last few months I have been using &lt;a href="https://www.vagrantup.com/"&gt;Vagrant&lt;/a&gt; and 
&lt;a href="http://www.ansible.com/configuration-management"&gt;Ansible&lt;/a&gt; for any new projects that I have to work on. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea behind vagrant is to allow you to isolate all the software requirements to run your code for different projects
inside separate virtual machines. Vagrant makes it easier to work on different projects with conflicting requirements by
isolating them in different virtual machines. For example, two different projects requiring different versions of MYSQL.
It also has the added benefit of not cluttering your actual machine with all the projects unique and different software 
requirements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ansible is a powerful automation tool that allows you to easily setup new (and old) servers with the required
software it needs. This makes setting up new enviroments a breeze.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The combination of Anisble and Vagrant is currently a real powerful way of setting up development
enviroments quickly. If you add the Ansible scripts to your source control, you will have the changing requirements
of your application setup in your source history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have recently taken the challenge of destroying my virtual machines every Monday and rebuilding it using Vagrant and
 Ansible. The idea being that I should be able to continue working within minutes and if that is not the case, updating
 the Ansible scripts with the required changes. This will help me make sure anything important required to work on the
 project is in source control, whether that be code, data or software setup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is currently my prefered method of working with the my-grocery-price-book-code. If you too are interested in this
sort of setup, I recommended you take a look at&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="https://bitbucket.org/grantspeelman/my-grocery-price-book.co.za/src/d43c1610845416273530eb526e038c42bb70b813/Vagrantfile?at=master&amp;amp;fileviewer=file-view-default#Vagrantfile-120"&gt;Vagrantfile&lt;/a&gt;
and the
&lt;a href="https://bitbucket.org/grantspeelman/my-grocery-price-book.co.za/src/d43c1610845416273530eb526e038c42bb70b813/ansible/?at=master"&gt;Ansible Scripts&lt;/a&gt;
of the my grocery price book code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also if you have not worked with either of the 2 before or would like to know more about them, I recommend you check
out their Getting Started pages:
&lt;a href="https://docs.vagrantup.com/v2/getting-started/"&gt;Vagrant&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://docs.ansible.com/ansible/intro_getting_started.html"&gt;Ansible&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Current System Architecture</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2015/09/09/system-architecture.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2015/09/09/system-architecture.html</id>
    <published>2015-09-09T02:00:00+02:00</published>
    <updated>2016-01-29T17:57:50+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Having a system architecture might seem like overkill for this project, but I am hoping it will help me keep the
system in my head and help make more insightful decisions. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I almost always find it easy to talk about system architecture when you have a diagram. So I decided to create one using
&lt;a href="https://www.draw.io/"&gt;draw.io&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="alt text" title="Grocery Price Book System Architecture" src="/images/GrocerySystemArch.svg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the goal is to link the traditional Grocery Price Book with the of Crowd Sourcing. This will hopefully make it
easier for people to share pricing information thus increasing the power of your Price Book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The system has been split into 2 main apps. The User Facing Price Book application part that will handle all the user 
specific information and a API to store all the pricing infomation. This should make it possible for vendors to load 
their pricing infomation into the API if they want to.This is all still mostly theory at the moment. 
Hoping to start eating my own dog food soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a slightly different note…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have recently completed 'viewing your prices' on the price book page which pulls its infomation from the API.
Things left to do is build the 'Shopping List' and completing the 'Price Compare' sections, then we should have 
our MVP.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The Free Time Pickle and discovering Roda</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2015/08/30/the-free-time-pickle.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2015/08/30/the-free-time-pickle.html</id>
    <published>2015-08-30T02:00:00+02:00</published>
    <updated>2016-01-29T17:57:50+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So doing this project during my free time has been quite a challenge for me so far
I usually have about 7 to 10 hours a week in the evenings to work on developing.
Usually I use this time to either mess around with a new technology or sometimes I find 
myself still doing work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been busy this week refactoring the grocery api to use the 
&lt;a href="https://github.com/jeremyevans/roda"&gt;roda&lt;/a&gt; which has turned into a bigger refactor than
I thought it would be (due to having to do the type casting myself). I must say I
do feel much better the way the code looks now and I do feel like the code is more 
under my control but from the outside I have not really added anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I realise I am doing these kinds of refactoring a bit early (putting the perfect project on ice) 
and I am more likely at the point where I have to let the technical debt build up until I have 
a working product. Who knows I might never change it and never have to pay back that technical debt?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am hoping to keep these kind of detours under control by taking some advice from a 
&lt;a href="http://programmers.stackexchange.com/a/76877"&gt;stackexchange answer&lt;/a&gt; and focus on getting
a working project that is usable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That all said, don't forget to check out &lt;a href="https://github.com/jeremyevans/roda"&gt;roda&lt;/a&gt;. 
Janko Marohnić &lt;a href="http://twin.github.io/introduction-to-roda/"&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; is a nice intro.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The Big Picture</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2015/08/24/the-big-picture.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2015/08/24/the-big-picture.html</id>
    <published>2015-08-24T02:00:00+02:00</published>
    <updated>2016-01-29T17:57:50+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So what am i trying to accomplish is building a online price book you can use for your grocery shopping 
If you don't know what a Price Book is I suggest you read &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Price_book"&gt;Wikipedia Definition&lt;/a&gt;
and Melanie Pinola's blog article on &lt;a href="http://lifehacker.com/how-to-save-the-most-money-on-your-grocery-budget-with-1518202640"&gt;How to Save the Most Money on Your Grocery Budget with a Price Book&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below I have a flow-chart (built with &lt;a href="http://www.draw.io/"&gt;draw.io&lt;/a&gt;) that shows you what a grocery price booker
has to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="alt text" title="Grocery Price Book Overview" src="/images/GroceryPriceBookOverview.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Yellow blocks are what all shoppers have to do while the Red blocks show what price bookers do in addition.
These very Red blocks make keeping a price book a serious discipline. So basically the goal of the WIP 
&lt;a href="http://www.my-grocery-price-book.co.za"&gt;my-grocery-price-book&lt;/a&gt; is to make keeping a price book less labour
intensive and hopefully using crowd sourcing to make it ever easier to maintain and start a grocery price book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully this has set the stage…&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
